Guide to the Gustav Henry Bliesner Papers 1934-1985
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 1: "My Life's Philosophy" volumes, first sequence, 1934-1967
  - Space and Information Systems Division Publication Style Guide; North American Aviation Inc., volume 179, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - The Geosciences Applied to Manned Lunar Exploration, Grumman (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Aircraft Exploration: Dr. J. Green Space Sciences Laboratory (report, 115 pages), volume 180, 1961 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - MSC Site Activation, Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corporation (report), volume 181, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Interface Control Documentation for Manned Spacecraft Center Space Environmental Simulation Laboratory (report) volume 182, undated (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Report of Foundation and Materials Fairbanks Operation Station Fairbanks, AK, volume 183, 1960 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Qualifications Inventory for Employees of North American Aviation Inc., volume 184, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Publications Preparation Guide Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corporation, volume 185, 1964 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Test Facility Requirements for LEM at the MSC Environmental Test Facilities (report, 65 pages), volume 186, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Training Booklet Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corporation, volume 187, undated (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - LEM Propulsion Training, volume 188, undated (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - LEM Memos and Specifications, volume 189 A-D, 1964 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - Bonneville Power Administration Report of Accomplishments of the Engineering Division, volume 190, 1940 April 13 (Chronicle of dam development and electrification in Pacific Northwest up to 1940) (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Design Analysis for Detroit Dam Power Plant Appendix D Electrical Design Notes, volume 191, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Advance Planning Report on Dry Dock No. 6 Puget Sound Naval Shipyard, Bremerton, WA (report), volume 192, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - The Colorado River (Comprehensive Departmental Report on the Development of Water Resources of the Colorado Basin for Review Prior to Submission to Congress, 293 pages, with accompanying maps), volume 193, undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Dams and Control Works, volume 194, 1938 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Opening our Bibles, volume 195, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Christ Today Lutheran World Federation, volume 196, undated (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - 10PAK: An Input-Output Package for Fortran IV, June 1965, Grumman Research Department Computing Report CR 65-6, volume 197, 1965 (Box 65, Folder 10)
- Series 2: "My Life's Philosophy" volumes, second sequence, 1965-1976
  - Situations, volume 163, 1975 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Civil Service Ratings State and Local, volume 163B, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - "Back Home," volume 163C, 1969 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Personal File, volume 166A, 1965-1967 (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
  - Personal File, volume 166C, 1965-1967 (Box 66, Folder 6-7)
  - Professional History and Experience Record of Gustav Henry Bliesner, to Accompany I.E.E.E. Fellow Form FC-1, volume 168, 1967 (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
  - Village Electrification in Southeast Asia, volume 170, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - City Engineer Newberg Oregon, volume 171A, 1967-1968 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - City Engineer Newberg Oregon, volume 171A, 1968-1969 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Swarthmore Subdivision, volume 172, 1967-1970 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Newberg Oregon Toastmasters, volume 174A, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Newberg Oregon Toastmasters, volume 174B-C, 1969-1970 (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
  - Hoover Park Improvements, volume 175, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - New Engineering Department, volume 176A, 1968-1977 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - My Rotary International Vocational, volume 177, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 5-6)
  - Job Offer, volume 178A, 1969 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - My Defense, volume 179A, 1969 (newspaper clippings and correspondence regarding Bliesner's removal from city engineer post in Newberg, OR) (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Dean of Engineering, volume 180, 1969-1974 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Street Improvement Project, volume 181A, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Street Improvement, volume 181B, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
  - New Engineering Department Proposals (Newberg, OR), volume 182, 1969 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Civil Service Forms, volume 183, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Community Facility Planning (Newberg, OR), volume 184, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Construction, volume 185A, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits to Accompany My Statement #171, volume 185B, 1972 (Box 70, Folder 2-3)
  - Urban Development (Newberg, OR), volume 186, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Engineering Study, volume 187, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Building and Concrete Pipeline Inspection (Newberg, OR), volume 188, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Getting a Job, volume 189, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Getting a Job, volume 189B, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Professor of Mathematics, volume 190, undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Professor of Electrical Engineering, volume 190, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Personnel Rules (Newberg, OR), volume 191, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Council Meeting, volume 192, 1970 June 1 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Life Insurance, volume 193, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 3-4)
  - The President, volume 194, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Anaheim Convention (IEEE), volume 195, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Underground Utilities and Electrical Systems, volume 196, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Example Conference Paper, volume 197, 1970 (includes paper about underground utilities and electrical systems) (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - A Job in 1971, volume 199, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Tried again, volume 200, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Bidding Low, volume 201, 1967-1970 (Box 72, Folder 2-3)
  - Spec Writing, volume 202, 1971 (includes notes, schematics, and blueprints about Vietnam, 1968-69) (Box 72, Folder 4-6)
  - VISTA (Action) Peace Corps, volume 203, 1971-1972 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Employer-Employee, volume 204, undated (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Client Consultant, volume 205, 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - City of Portland, volume 206, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - REA (Rural Electrification Authority), volume 207, 1971-1973 (Box 73, Folder 3-4)
  - REA, volume 207B, undated (Box 73, Folder 5-6)
  - ADM Assistant, volume 208, 1971-1975 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - A Vigil Scouter, volume 210, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - The Monster, volume 211, 1972 (includes information about Strategic Arms Limitations talks SALT and other Cold War topics) (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Misc. University of Portland, volume 212, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Problems-Syllabus University of Portland, volume 212, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Portland General and Underground Systems, volume 212A, undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Problems, Syllabus, Examples P.C.C., volume 212C, 1975-1976 (Box 74, Folder 6-7)
  - Problems, Syllabus, Examples P.C.C., volume 212C (continued) (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
  - Electrical Engineering Syllabus, Work Study Program, University of Portland, volume 212D, undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Principal Lecturer "Electrical Engineering," volume 213, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 4-5)
  - Principal Senior Engineer, volume 214, 1973-1974 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Updating, volume 215, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 7-8)
  - County Administrative Candidate (Yamhill County, OR), volume 216, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Bliesners, Hauers, Olsons, volume 217, 1973 (Family history information) (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - ALC District Convention Pacific Lutheran University, volume 218, undated (Box 76, Folder 3-4)
  - Head, volume 219, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Private Practice, volume 220, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Creation, volume 222, 1973 (Lecture notes on creation, George Fox College, OR) (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Political Science, volume 223, 1973 (Lecture notes, George Fox College) (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - City Administrative Candidate, volume 224, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - CH2M-Hill-GB, volume 225, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Bliesner, volume 226, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - George Fox College, volume 227, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 3-4)
  - International Executive News, volume 228, 1964-1974 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Bliesner Engineering Papers, volume 229, 1974-1975 (Box 77, Folder 6-7)
  - Educating Intern Professional Engineers, volume 230, undated (Box 78, Folder 1-2)
  - Syllabi Bliesner, volume 233, 1974 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - P.C.C. Syllabi, volume 237, 1975 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Misc. 1975-76, volume 238, 1975-1976 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - File Outline, volume 119 (Revised from series 1 volume 54), undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Office Files, undated
  - Personal files, corresponding to file outline in volume 54 (Box 79-88)
  - Personal Files (Box 88-89)
- Series 4: Subject files, 1947-1985
  - Subseries 4.1: Education, 1947-1970
    - Rural Electrification Transmission and Distribution Loop and Network Services (Bliesner Ph.D.), 1963 (Box 90, Folder 1-2)
    - Ph.D. thesis plates, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Academic Log, 1950-1957 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Laboratory Instructions, 1947 (Electrical Engineering Department, Farragut College) (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Continuing Education, 1968 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Electrical Engineering Lab Instructions, University of Portland, 1954 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Underground Lighting, 1970 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Colleges and Universities, 1959-1964 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - UCLA, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Northridge College, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4.2: Papers and reports, 1957-1970
    - Essay (manuscript and revisions), Electrical and Electronic Education with Professional Practice, undated (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Desert Indians, 1957 (Includes paper by Bliesner, Columbia River Basin map, California Central Valley Project information) (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Ground Support Electrical Precision Power (report), undated (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Registered Professional Engineers in Government (essay), undated (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Electrical Engineering Review Space Physics Exo Biology, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Electrical Engineering Review Space Physics Exo Biology, 1964 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Report on hydro-ecological survey for Cornell, Howland, Hays, and Merrifield Consulting Engineers, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Village electrification in southeast Asia, 1968-1969 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Interim report 230-kv transmission economic study, 1945 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Power to the People (papers on energy), 1971 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Seminar Expositions, circa 1960s (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Electric Service, circa 1960s (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Papers presented, 1960s (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Convention papers, 1960s (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Underground Distribution IEEE, 1968-1969 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Underground Utilities and Electrical Systems, IEEE, 1969-1970 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4.3: Societies, 1957-1975
    - Young Engineers Meeting, 1960 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1959 (Box 93, Folder 3-4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 93, Folder 5-6)
    - Engineer Societies, 1970 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Clippings and articles related to AIEE, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - American Society for Engineering Education, 1975 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Typ. Reg.'l. Papers, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - AAAS, IEEE, NSPE, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.4: Military Engineering, 1952-1966
    - Automated Civil Engineering Program Evaluation Review Technique (ACEPERT), USAF Guide, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Documents of G.H. Bliesner for Thailand License in Electrical Engineering (Communications), 1966 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Cost Estimate for Army Base Development AN.KHE, RVN, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Specifications for Army Base Development AN.KHE, RVN, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Power Study for Ubon Air Base Thailand, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Marine Corps Recruit Depot Book, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Corroborative Report for GS-14 Electrical Engineering rating, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Military construction pricing guide, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Electrical distribution standards Engineer Corps Alaska Dist., 1952 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Electrical distribution standards Engineer Corps Seattle Dist., 1960 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.5: Boeing, North American Aviation, NASA, 1955-1974
    - Development and Tests of Wire Assemblies MA-2 System, 1955 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Estimate and Calculations for G.S.E. Proofing Area, Seal Beach, CA, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Guide Specifications for Indoor Type 120-208 volt, 400 cycle 30 AC power, circa 1960s (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Management, circa 1962-1965 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Fire Protection, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Safety Standards, circa 1964 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Addendums, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Research and Tests, circa 1962-1964 (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Specifications, circa 1958 (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Proposed Plan, circa 1963 (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Master Planning, circa 1960s (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Electric Ground Support, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Job Logs, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Las Cruces, NM, 1963 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Saturn B Tests Apollo Downey, 1962-1963 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - B-3 Downey, circa 1962 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - B-6 Downey, circa 1963-1964 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Reference material, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Slauson, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Seal Beach, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - First Five Years, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Specifications, circa 1964 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Projects, 1958-1964 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - North American Aviation, 1965 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Organization Charts, 1964-1965 (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - Reports, 1963-1965 (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - NASA Design Criteria for Rehabilitation of Electrical Power System phase 2 and 3 Plant 16, Downey, CA, 1974 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 4.6: Contract Documents, Civil Engineering, 1957-1985
    - Contract Documents for Northwood Park Subdivision Improvements (pamphlet), 1968 (Box 96, Folder 16)
    - Addendum to Northwood Park Subdivision Improvements, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 17)
    - Contract Documents for Earthfill Dam (Joseph Rogers Dam), Newberg, OR (pamphlet), 1969 (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - Contract Documents for the Construction of a Drilled Water Well and Modifications to an Existing Well, Newberg, OR (pamphlet), 1969 (Box 96, Folder 19)
    - Contract Documents for Eight Inch Diameter Pipeline from Elliot Road to County Road no. 59 (pamphlet), 1969 (Box 96, Folder 20)
    - Contract Documents for Conference Ground Improvements, Church of the Nazarene, Woodburn, OR (pamphlet), 1969 (Box 96, Folder 21)
    - Comprehensive land use plan, Newberg, OR (pamphlet), 1985 (Box 96, Folder 22)
    - Water works manual and catalog file (pamphlet), 1970 (Box 96, Folder 23)
    - Newberg city budget, 1968-1969 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Contract documents for the construction of exploratory wells City of Newberg, OR (pamphlet), 1968 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Yamhill county planning guide (pamphlet), 1968 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Subdivision Improvement Requirements planning bulletin (pamphlet), 1970 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Potential Industrial Sites in Yamhill County, OR (pamphlet), 1970 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - City of Newberg Water Supply System Improvements, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - American Standard Definitions of Electrical Terms (pamphlet), 1957 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Biennial reports, Oregon state board of engineering examiners, 1969-1971 (Box 97, Folder 8-9)
    - Annual reports, Washington State Board of Registration for Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors, 1969-1970 (Box 97, Folder 10-11)
    - Guide to Consulting Engineer Services for Public Works (pamphlet), undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Hydroelectric Dams in Pacific Northwest (pamphlet), circa 1960s (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Handbook on treaty with Canada for development of the Columbia River (pamphlet), circa 1971 (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Contract Documents for 99-W Hulet Deborah Street Sanitary Sewage improvements, 1971 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Contract Documents for Fulton Street Villa Road Improvements (Box 97, Folder 16)
    - Contract Documents for Second Street Improvements, 1971 (Box 97, Folder 17)
    - Everything You Always Wanted to Know about BPA (pamphlet), 1971 (Box 97, Folder 18)
    - The Trojan Nuclear Power Plant (brochure), undated (Box 97, Folder 19)
    - Contract Documents for Sewage Collection and Treatment Facility, Newberg, OR, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Contract Documents for Hess Creek-Springbrook Sanitary Sewer Collection System Improvements, Newberg, OR, 1970 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Contract Documents for Sewage System Improvements Newberg, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Swarthmore Subdivision, 1964 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Newberg City Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Specifications for Annex Remodeling Fire Station and City Hall, Newberg, OR, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - General Electric Circuit Protective Components catalog, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Consulting engineers' brochures, circa 1970s (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Underground utilities planning paper, circa 1960s (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Engineering education materials, 1970s (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 4.7: Engineering files, circa 1957-1973
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Includes letters to Washington State University regarding his papers) (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Incinerators, undated (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles County Air Pollution Control District, 1960s (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Plant Engineering Procedure, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Flood Control, 1965 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Power and Lighting, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Precision power regulator, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - 400 N Generators, circa 1960-1961 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Generators and Motors, circa 1960s (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Rectifiers, circa 1964-1965 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Design and Construction, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - NASA Analysis Chart, 1964-1965 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - University of Portland, 1973 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - In-service Training, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Reliability, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Communications, 1963-1964 (Box 99, Folder 16)
    - Electric Heating, 1962-1963 (Box 99, Folder 17)
    - Corrosion Studies, 1950s-1960s (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - Photographs (negatives), undated (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - State of California licensing board, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 21)
    - Federal Power Commission press releases, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 22)
    - Copper wire characteristics, undated (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Research (skid-mounted generator pamphlet), undated (Box 99, Folder 24)
    - Control and circuit protection, 1962-1965 (Box 99, Folder 25)
    - Insulation, circa 1957-1963 (Box 99, Folder 26)
    - Distribution and Transmission, 1958 (Box 99, Folder 27)
    - Utilities, undated (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4.8: Personal Journals, 1951-1970
    - Personal journals; 1951, 1953 (Box 100, Folder 2-3)
    - Log Book, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Resume, 1970 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 100, Folder 6-7)
    - Surplus Properties, 1960-1965 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Biographical information, notes about papers, miscellaneous; circa 1960s-1970s (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Consulting Practice, 1957-1965 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Personnel, 1963-1964 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Notebooks and log books (including news clippings), 1965-1969 (Box 101, Folder 1-8)
    - Notebooks and log books (including news clippings), 1965-1969 (continued) (Box 102, Folder 1-2)
    - Biographical information, correspondence, Toastmasters materials, and miscellaneous; 1974-1977 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1968 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.9: Miscellaneous, 1965-1973
    - Correspondence, resumes, and miscellaneous (includes Richard Nixon campaign materials), 1968-1972 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Biographical information, correspondence, and miscellaneous; 1972-1973 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Engineering (pamphlets), 1968-1970 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - State and county fairs and miscellaneous (pamphlets), circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - German magazines, 1965-1969 (Box 103, Folder 5)